Jiangliu Wang

I am currently a Postdoctoral Researcher in the CUHK T Stone Robotics Institute at the Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK). My research interests include self-supervised representation learning, video understanding, multimodal learning, and related applications on robotics.

Education

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

2015 - 2020

Ph.D. in Mechanical and Automation Engineering

Supported by Hong Kong PhD Fellowship Scheme (HKPFS)

Advisor: Yun-hui Liu
Nanjing University

2011 - 2015

B.Eng. in Control and Systems Engineering

Advisor: Wei Li

Publications

1. ————. Research on self-supervised audio-visual representation learning.

Jiangliu Wang, Jianbo Jiao, Haoang Li, Di Kang, and Yun-hui Liu Submitted to Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS). 2021.

2. Self-supervised Video Representation Learning by Uncovering Spatio-temporal Statistics.

Jiangliu Wang*, Jianbo Jiao*, Linchao Bao, Shengfeng He, Wei Liu, and Yun-hui Liu.

Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (T-PAMI). 2021.

3. Self-Supervised Video Representation Learning by Pace Prediction.

Jiangliu Wang, Jianbo Jiao, and Yun-hui Liu

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV). 2020.

4. Contrastive Learning of Video Representations with Temporally Adversarial Examples.

Yibing Song, Tian Pan, Tianyu Yang, **Jiangliu Wang**, Chongjian Ge, Wenhao Jiang, and Wei Liu Submitted to Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (T-PAMI).

5. Self-supervised Spatio-temporal Representation Learning for Videos by Predicting Motion and Appearance statistics.

Jiangliu Wang, Jianbo Jiao, Linchao Bao, Shengfeng He, Yun-hui Liu and Wei Liu.

Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR). 2019.

6. View-invariant human action recognition based on a 3d bio-constrained skeleton model.

Qiang Nie, Jiangliu Wang, Xin Wang, and Yun-hui Liu.

Transactions on Image Processing (TIP). 2019

7. Kinematics Features for 3D Action Recognition Using Two-Stream CNN.

Jiangliu Wang and Yunhui-Liu.

World Congress on Intelligent Control and Automation (WCICA). 2018.

8. Motion patterns and phase-transition of a defender–intruder problem and optimal interception strategy of the defender.

Jiangliu Wang and Wei Li.

Communications in Nonlinear Science and Numerical Simulation. 2015.

Tier 1 journal in applied mathematics.

Patent

1. Image coding method, action recognition method, and computer device.

Jiangliu Wang, Kebin Yuan, and Yun-hui Liu.

Patent WO2019120108A1.

Work Experience and Internships

Postdoctoral Researcher CUHK T Stone Robotics Institute Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK) Work on self-supervised representation learning Work on fine-grained video understanding for robotics	Oct. 2020 - Present
Research Intern at Tencent AI Lab Computer Vision Group, Tencent, Shenzhen Mentor: Linchao Bao and Wei Liu Worked on self-supervised video representation learning	May 2018 - May 2019
Research Assistant at CUHK Worked on video understanding and its applications on robotics Collaborated with <i>HUAWEI Noah's Ark Lab</i> on children caring robot Collaborated with <i>KOKORO Co., Ltd. Japan</i> on humanoid robot	July 2015 - Sept. 2020
Research Assistant at Nanjing University Department of Control and Systems Engineering Advisor: Wei Li Worked on defense–intrusion interaction optimization problem	Oct. 2013 - July 2014
Selected Awards	

Academic Services

Hong Kong PhD Fellowship Scheme (HKPFS)

First-class Scholarship for Outstanding Students of NJU

Excellent Undergraduate Student of NJU

Conference Reviewer: CVPR 2021, ICCV 2021, ICML 2021 Workshop on SSL, NeurIPS 2020 Workshop on SSL, ICRA 2020, IROS 2019.

2015 - 2019

2012-2014

2015

Journal Reviewer: IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems (TNNLS), IEEE Robotics and Automation Magazine (RAM).